Ignacio Suay Mas

July 15,1985

Mobile: 07511294910

Web: http://www.ignaciosuay.com/ **Address:** 82, Charles Street, Ox4 3AS (OXFORD) **GitHub:** https://github.com/ignacioSuay

SUMMARY

Ignacio Suay is a software engineer with 8 years of industry experience in building end-to-end web applications with Java, Spring, Hibernate, AngularJS and many other software technologies.

Email: ignacio.suay@gmail.com

Currently, he is working with the Worldwide Anti-malarial Resistance Network (WWARN) at the University of Oxford providing the much-needed comprehensive, timely, quality-assured intelligence needed to track the emergence and spread of malaria drug resistance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Oxford – WorldWide Antimalarial Resistance Network

03/2014 - Present Oxford, UK

Software Engineer

- Develop web applications, end to end, with Java, Hibernate and Spring (Data, MVC and Security)
- Implement front-end user interfaces using GWT, JavaScript and AngularJS.
- Design and maintain Relational Databases
- Design and implement Open source Framework for data visualization
- Help the team achieve the goals as Scrum master
- Supervise junior software developers

Allocate Software - Realtime Health

10/2012 - 03/2014

Oxford, UK

Integration Software Engineer

- Design, develop, test, implement, maintain, support and code enhancements to HL7 interfaces.
- Healthcare software development using Java, Spring, Hibernate and Flex.
- Integration Interfaces with Apache Camel, ActiveMQ and CXF Web Services.
- Technical documentation for all phases of integration: analysis, design, development, unit testing, integration testing and go-live support.
- Agile Software development for healthcare.

Brain Research Imaging Centre - University Of Edinburgh

03/2012 - 10/2012

Edinburgh UK

Data Analyst

- EEG data analysis Lineal Algebra in computational biomedical data.
- Outliers detection in multivariate data.
- Principal Components Analysis (PCA).
- Iterative Re-weighted Least Square.

Institute of Robotics and Information Technology

10/2007 - 09/2010 Valencia, Spain

Software Engineer

- Web application reporter in traffic mortality accidents using Java, Flex, Spring and Hibernate.
- Statistical Analysis of traffic accidents in Spain using R.
- Database quality web application tool.
- Statistical Yearbook of traffic accidents in Spain

Engineers Without Borders

10/2006 - 10/2007

Volunteer Engineer

Valencia, Spain

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- Java
- JavaScript
- SQL

Front-End Technologies:

- AngularJS
- JQuery
- Google Web Toolkit
- Bootstrap
- Compass
- Grunt and Bower
- HTML5 and CSS

Databases:

- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Oracle
- H2

Back-End Technologies:

- Spring (Boot, JPA, Security, MVC Rest)
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Liquibase
- Web services (SOAP and REST)
- Apache Camel and ActiveMQ

Environment:

- Agile Software development
- Test-driven development
- Jenkins CI
- Tomcat
- Git
- Jetty
- Amazon Web Services
- Gerrit Core Review
- Linux/Mac Os

PROJECTS

First Certificate Tests

Web application for preparing the First English Certificate.

Technology stack:

- Databases: MongoDB and H2
- Spring Boot, Data JPA, MVC REST
- Responsive Web design with Bootstrap, Compass and CSS
- AngularJS and HTML5
- Bower, Grunt and Karma

Maps Surveyor Framework

Maps Surveyor is a mapping platform for visualising data to support statistical reporting, public health surveillance, and health research. It is an Open Source Framework used by different projects like the K13 Surveyor or the Malaria Molecular Surveyor.

Technology stack:

- Google Web ToolKit and Bootstrap in the client side
- Java and Remote Procedure Calls in the server side
- Apache Lucene Core search engine

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Polytechnic University of Valencia and University of Valencia

Biomedical Engineering, Master Degree

University of Valencia

Computer Engineering, Bachelor's Degree

University of Valencia

Telecommunications Engineer Telematics, Bachelor's Degree

09/2010 - 09/2012 (First Class Honours)

09/2003 - 07/2009

(First Class Honours)

09/2003 - 07/2009

(First Class Honours)

CERTIFICATIONS

MongoDB M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers

03/2015

Oracle

07/2012

1Z0-047 Oracle Database SQL expert Certification